Register of the Aleksandr Polovet͡s papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- SOUND RECORDINGS, 1981-2016
  - Part 2
    - Petrova, Liubov, 1995 (Box 16)
      Conversation about the mentalist’s use of her paranormal abilities to diagnose and treat illness. 3 files. Duration: 1 hour (30 min. + 20 min. + 10 min.).
    - Polovets, Alexander, 1991 (Box 16)
      Appearance on Moscow radio about the illness and operation of Bulat Okudzhava to dispel all the rumors regarding them. 1 file. Duration: 7 minutes.
    - Postolov, Anatoly, 1999 (Box 16)
      Conversation about Russian-language singer-songwriters in Los Angeles, the influence of Bulat Okudzhava and Vladimir Vysotsky, and generational differences regarding songs. 1 file. Duration: 17 minutes.
    - Rachikhin, Vladimir, 1985 (Box 16)
      Conversation about his work with director Sergei Bondarchuk, his escape to the USA through Mexico, and the start of his new life in Los Angeles. 2 files. Duration: 45 minutes.
    - Rachikhina, Evgeniia, 1989 (Box 16)
      Conversation with Vladimir Rachikhin’s ex-wife about their marriage and its collapse. 2 files. Duration: 1 hour, 10 minutes.
    - Roziner, Felix, 1992 (Box 16)
      Conversation about his encounters with Lithuanian politician Vytautas Landsbergis, members of the Lithuanian intelligentsia, the lives of different ethnic groups, and the issue of emigration. 2 files. Duration: 1 hour, 10 minutes (46 min. + 24 min.).
    - Rozovsky (Rosovskiy), Mark, 1991 (Box 16)
      Conversations on a broad variety of issues related to the arts, politics and social conditions in Russia. 5 files. Duration: 2 hours (50 min. + 6 min. + 32 min. + 32 min.).
    - Semenov, Aleksei, 1983 (Box 16)
      Conversation with the son of Andrei Sakharov’s wife from her former marriage about his emigration, the Sakharovs, and the potential for American influence to improve their conditions of exile in the city of Gorky. 1 file. Duration: 30 minutes.
    - Semenov, Iulian, 1990 (Box 16)
      Conversation touching upon the magazine “Sovershenno sekretno”, the detective genre, aspects of the writer’s biography, and current conditions in the Soviet Union. 2 files. Duration 55 minutes.
    - Sevela, Efraim, 1998 (Box 16)
      Conversation about Sevela’s books, his life, his meetings with readers, and politics. 2 files. Duration: 1 hour, 55 minutes (25 min. + 45 min. + 45 min.).
    - Sharansky, Natan, 1999 (Box 16)
      Conversation (in English) on a wide variety of topics related to the condition of Jews in the world and in Russia, and the possibility of improved Russo-Israeli relations. 2 files. Duration: 1 hour (30 min. + 30 min.).
    - Shargorodsky, Lev, 1999 (Box 16)
      Conversation about the Swiss national character, humorists, the theme of Jewishness in his work, his difficulties in working in the USSR, and the main areas of focus of his joint literary work with his brother. 2 files. Duration: 1 hour, 20 minutes (65 min. + 15 min.).
    - Shtromas, Alexander, 1999 (Box 16)
      Conversation regarding the situation in Europe, especially in Bosnia and Kosovo, and his take on the Russian economy. 1 file. Duration: 43 minutes.
    - Sokolov, Sasha, 1981 (Box 16)
      Conversation about this writer’s creative process, how he became a writer, his emigration, and his need for inner freedom. 2 files. Duration: 1 hour, 3 minutes (32 min. + 31 min.).
    - Suslov, Ilya, 1998 (Box 16)
      Conversation about his work at “Iunost’” magazine and “Literaturnaia gazeta” with the best Soviet satirists and what motivated him to emigrate. 1 file. Duration: 1 hour, 5 minutes.
    - Suslov, Mikhail, 2016 (Box 16)
      Conversation about his emigration to the USA, his search for his Soviet-made movies at the Pacific Film Archive, and his work as a motion picture director in America. 2 files. Duration: 1 hour (30 min. + 30 min.).
    - Synagogue, 1990 (Box 16)
      Conversation with several activists of the Russian-language Jewish community in Los Angeles about building a new Chabad synagogue and its future social, spiritual and cultural significance. 1 file. Duration: 42 minutes.
    - Urin, Viktor, 1985 (Box 16)
      A reading by the author of some of his erotic poetry and a conversation about his work and the possibility of publishing a small volume of his verse. 1 file. Duration: 30 minutes.
    - Voinovich, Vladimir, 1981 (Box 16)
      A recording of his presentation at the Literature in Exile conference in Los Angeles. 1 file. Duration: Not indicated.
- BULAT OKUDZHAVA FILE, 1978-2015, undated
  Photographs and audiovisual materials.
  - Bibliography, 2002 (Box-folder 17: 1)
    Lists publications devoted to Bulat Okudzhava in the Russian-language press in the United States from 1989 to 1999 held in the personal archive of V. Yurovsky.
  - Photographs, 1978-2004, undated
    Packets of photographs mainly chronicling Okudzhava’s 1991 trip to the United States.
    - Inventory prepared by Alexander Polovet͡s providing detailed information on each photograph (Box-folder 17: 2)
    - Bulat Okudzhava's first visit to Los Angeles, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 17: 3)
      3 color prints depicting Okudzhava with Alexander Polovets, Yakov Skliansky, Ilya Baskin, and Victor Shulman.
    - Bulat Okudzhava's Hollywood High School concert, 1991 (Box-folder 17: 4)
      9 color prints depicting Okudzhava performing with guitar and the concert audience.
    - Bulat Okudzhava in Marina Del Rey, Santa Monica, and Venice, California, 1991 (Box-folder 17: 5)
      18 color prints depicting Okudzhava with his wife Olga, son Bulat, Jr., Alexander Polovets, Alexander Polovets’ mother, Ilya Baskin, and Liliya Sokolova.
    - Bulat Okudzhava at an open-air art exhibit in the Los Angeles area, 1991 (Box-folder 17: 6)
      7 color prints depicting Okudzhava with his wife, his son, and Alexander Polovets.
    - Bulat Okudzhava at the editorial office of Panorama newspaper, 1991 (Box-folder 17: 7)
      7 color prints of Okudzhava, his wife, his son, Alexander Polovets, Ilya Baskin, Peter Vegin, Irakli Kverekadze and others.
    - Bulat Okudzhava in Chinatown, 1991 (Box-folder 17: 8)
      4 color prints depicting Okudzhava, his wife, and his son.
    - Bulat Okudzhava in Tarzana, California, 1991 (Box-folder 17: 8)
      9 color prints depicting Okudzhava, his wife, his son, Alexander Polovets, and Polovets’ granddaughter Daniella.
    - Bulat Okudzhava at Rustam Ibragimbekov’s Santa Monica restaurant, 1991 (Box-folder 17: 10)
      5 color prints depicting Okudzhava, his wife, his son, Alexander Polovets, Ilya Baskin, Rustam Imbragimbekov, and his wife Shohred.
    - Bulat Okudzhava in the Fairfax District of Los Angeles, 1991 (Box-folder 17: 11)
      19 color prints depicting Okudzhava, his wife and his son at the Michael Jackson Private High School and at Plummer Park Auditorium.
    - Bulat Okudzhava and his family at Disneyland, 1991 (Box-folder 17: 12)
      19 color prints depicting Okudzhava, his family, and Yakov Skliansky.
    - Bulat Okudzhava at Ilya Baskin’s home, 1991 (Box-folder 17: 13)
      10 color prints depicting Okudzhava, his family, Ilya Baskin, and Alexander Polovets’ mother.
    - Bulat Okudzhava at the Huntington Library, San Marino, California, 1991 (Box-folder 17: 14)
      4 color prints depicting Okudzhava and his wife in the library’s gardens.
    - Bulat Okudzhava at San Vincente Hospital before and after his operation, 1991 (Box-folder 17: 15)
      29 color prints depicting Okudzhava at the hospital with his wife, nurses and doctors, and at Alexander Polovets’ home with Dr, Yuri Busi, Alexander Polovets, and Polovets’ mother.
    - Bulat Okudzhava at Alexander Polovets’ home, 1991 (Box-folder 17: 16)
      10 color prints depicting Okudzhava, his wife, Ilya Baskin, Liliya Sokolova, Vladimir and Tamara Aleynikov, Peter Todorovsky, Yakov Skliansky, Peter Vegin, Alexander Polovets, his mother, and granddaughter Daniella.
    - Bulat Okudzhava in Boston and New York, 1991 (Box-folder 17: 17)
      30 color prints depicting Okudzhava, his wife and son, Alexander Polovets, Ilya Baskin, Nina Arndt, Yuri Ponomarevsky, and others.
    - Bulat Okudzhava performs at Alexander Polovets’ home, 1991 (Box-folder 17: 18)
      8 color prints depicting Okudzhava, accompanied on the piano by his son, playing the guitar and singing for a small audience two days before his heart operation.
    - Bulat Okudzhava in the backyard of Alexander Polovets’ home, 1991 (Box-folder 17: 19)
      12 color prints depicting Okudzhava, his wife Olga, Savelik Kuramarov, Si Frumkin, Lidia Kogan, Mihail and Lidia Feinstein, Cameron Hakimov, Yakov Skliansky, Liliya Sokolova and others.
    - Bulat Okudzhava at Mihail and Lidia Feinsstein’s condominium in Marina Del Rey, 1991 (Box-folder 17: 20)
      6 color prints depicting Okudzhava (after his operation) and his wife with Mihail and Lidia Feinstein, and Alexander and Lidia Borisov.
    - Bulat Okudzhava in Century City, 1991 (Box-folder 17: 21)
      6 color prints depicting Okudzhava, his wife, his son, and Alexander Polovets in front of two skyscrapers.
    - Bulat Okudzhava at Peredelkino, Russia, 1991 (Box-folder 17: 22)
      8 color prints depicting Okudzhava with writer Anatoli Rybakov and his wife, journalist Irina Ryshina, and an unidentified journalist from East Germany.
    - Bulat Okudzhava Fund in Moscow, 2004 (Box-folder 17: 23)
      5 color prints Yegor Gaidar, Irina Lesnevskaya, Anatoly Pristavkin, Okudzhava’s wife Olga, Alexander Polovets, and an assistant.
    - Bulat Okudzhava statue, undated (1998 or later) (Box-folder 17: 24)
      2 color prints depicting Alexander Polovets holding a statue of Bulat Okudzhava. Packet also included of photo of Olga Okudzhava with dolls.
    - Bulat Okudzhava at a restaurant, 1991 (Box-folder 17: 25)
      1 print depicting Okudzhava having a meal in a restaurant during a trip to the East Coast.
    - Bulat Okudzhava and Galina Ohotina, undated (Box-folder 17: 26)
      1 color print depicting them having a meal with Liliya Sokolova.
    - Bulat Okudzhava at Plummer Park, West Hollywood, California, 1991 (Box-folder 17: 27)
      1 color print depicting Okudzhava, his son, and a technician preparing for a concert.
  - Index prints, 2012-2015 (Box-folder 17: 28)
    Selected prints of the prints in the preceding folders.
  - Negatives, 1991-2007 (Box-folder 17: 29)
    Negatives to the prints in the preceding folders as well as some unprinted negatives of memorial concerts and events for Bulat Okudzhava in Los Angeles and Peredelkino, Russia.
  - Sound and videorecordings, 1991-2007, undated
    - Audio cassette “Bulat on American Radio” (5M), 1991 (Box-folder 18: 1)
      Contains a KABC Los Angeles radio host requesting support for payment of Okudzhava’s hospital bills.
    - Audio cassette (5N), undated (Box-folder 18: 2)
      Contains a collection of Okudzhava's music.
    - Audio cassette (5O), 1999 (Box-folder 18: 3)
      Contains a 90-minute interview conducted by Aoexander Polovets with Naum Korzhavin regarding Bulat Okudzhava.
    - Audio cassette "Bulat" (5P), undated (Box-folder 18: 4)
      Contains a message on Alexander Povets’ answering machine regarding Okudzhava, as well as a recording of a phone call from Okudzhava to Alexander Polovets.
    - Audio cassette (5Q), 1991 (Box-folder 18: 5)
      Contains a Voice of America “Washington Encounter” program in which Okudzhava is interviewed with a group of artists. Recorded after Okudzhava’s operation, he discusses his visits to the United States in 1979, 1987, 1990 and 1991.
    - Audio cassette (5R), 1991 (Box-folder 18: 6)
      Contains a discussion with Dr. Busi in Okudzhava’s presence after his operation.
    - Audio cassette (5S), undated (Box-folder 18: 7)
      Contains an Ekho Mosky interview with Alexander Polovets regarding Okudzhava.
    - Audio cassette "Bulat" part 2 (5T), undated (Box-folder 18: 8)
      Contains an interview with Okudzhava by Alexander Polovets.
    - DVD (5E), 1991 May 23 (Box-folder 18: 9)
      Contains a concert given by Okudzhava at the home of Alexander Polovets.
    - CD-RW (5U), undated (Box-folder 18: 10)
      Contains the opening of the memorial statue for Okudzhava on the Arbat in Moscow.
    - DVD "Actor Sichkin, Bulat" (5V), 2007 (Box-folder 18: 11)
      Contains an interview with Okudzhava as well as a memorial concert featuring other artists performing Okudzhava material.
    - DVDs "A night for Bulat" in 2 parts (5W), undated (Box-folder 18: 12)
      Contains an outdoor concert at Rehelgaus Theater in Moscow with a series of artists performing Okudzhava material.
    - DVD "Presentation of Bulat book by Alexander Polovets" (5X), 2004 (Box-folder 18: 13)
      Disc has no sound.
    - CD "1969 concert of Bulat in Central House of Writers in Moscow" (5Y) (Box-folder 18: 14)
    - CD "Bulat, Akhmadulin" (5Z) (Box-folder 18: 15)
      Contains selected poetry readings in Moscow, with Okudzhava reading first.
    - CD "O Bulate" (6A) (Box-folder 18: 16)
      Contains a performance by Elena Kamburova.
    - 8mm Video "Bulat performance at Polovets' home" (5A), 1991 May 24 (Box-folder 19: 1)
      Contains many songs and an extensive question and answer session.
    - VHS "Bulat interview" (5B), late 1960s or 1970s (Box-folder 19: 2)
      Contains Okudzhava being interviewed by Miroslava Sverdlova and a young Okudzhava reading his poetry and playing a guitar on a television show.
    - VHS "Bulat assorted" (5C), 1991 (Box-folder 19: 3)
      Contains Okudzhava’s performance at Alexander Polovets’ home, scenes of Okudzhava at Venice Beach watching and listening to African-American street singers, touring Rodeo Drive and Chinatown.
    - VHS "Bulat Okudzhava Fund" (5D), 1960s-1990s (Box-folder 19: 4)
      Contains excerpts from Okudzhava’s films and interviews.
    - VHS "Bulat Festival in Moscow,", 2005-2006 (Box-folder 19: 5)
    - PAL tape "Peredelkino" (5H), 2001 June 16 (Box-folder 19: 6)
    - VHS "Gala concert in honor of Bulat" (5J), 1998 September 18 (Box-folder 19: 7)
      Contains performances by Moscow and Leningrad bards at the Polytechnic Museum.
    - VHS "Festival in honor of Bulat" (5K), 2001 September 6 (Box-folder 19: 8)
    - PAL tape "Bulat on TV" (Moscow) (5L) (Box-folder 19: 9)
    - 2 VHS tapes (6C) (Box-folder 19: 10-11)
      Contains commercials for Panorama newspaper on American television featuring Mikhail Kazakov, Bulat Okudzhava, and Arkady Arkanov, as well as a “Behind the Scenes” Panorama commercial with Okudzhava and Anatoly Gladilin.
    - VHS "Bulat, Ribakov, Peredelkino" (6E) (Box-folder 19: 12)
      Contains a documentary film for television.